appen.com.au 2017-06-05

# Appen: Fuel up your machine learning with high quality data

## 1\. Scope of the Privacy Policy

Appen Limited (“Appen”) considers the keeping of personal information private and confidential an extremely important issue and is strongly committed to protecting your privacy while using our website(s). Appen Limited is required to comply with the Australian Privacy Principles (APPs) in the _Privacy Act 1988_ (Cth) (Privacy Act). 

Our Privacy Policy tells you what information we collect when you visit our Website, how we use, share and protect it, what choices you have about how the information is used, and how you can access and update that information. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use our Website. This Privacy Policy applies to personally identifiable information collected on our Website where this Privacy Policy is posted. Certain aspects of this Privacy Policy also apply to the personally identifiable information we collect offline.

For purposes of this Privacy Policy, “personally identifiable information” means information that identifies a particular individual, such as name, postal address, e-mail address, and phone number.

## 2\. Collection of Personal Information

### Personally identifiable information we collect

Appen is required to collect personal information only by lawful and fair means. Where possible we will collect personal information we require directly from you. There are many features on this Website for which no registration is required. However, if you are interested in obtaining information, products or services from Appen, or in participating in certain activities on this Website (such as registering to qualify to become an Appen independent contractor), you may need to provide us with information about yourself. For example, if you register to qualify to become an independent contractor, we ask for your name, postal address, e-mail address, telephone number and payment details. In addition, we may combine personally identifiable information that you have provided to us with other information that is publicly available or that we receive from other reputable sources.

### Other Information Collected Through Technology

In addition to information you choose to provide to us, we also collect non-personally identifiable information through technology to make our site more interesting and useful to you. For instance, when you come to our site, we collect your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address. An IP address is often associated with the portal through which you enter the Internet, like your ISP (internet service provider). Standing alone, your IP address is not personally identifiable. At times, we also use IP addresses to collect information regarding the frequency with which our visitors visit various parts of our sites. We may combine this information with personally identifiable information that you have provided to us and/or with other information that is publicly available or that we receive from other reputable sources, in order to make our Website and communications more targeted to your interests.

Most internet browsers are set to accept cookies. If you prefer not to receive them, you can adjust your internet browser to reject cookies. Rejecting cookies can, however, limit the functionality of our website.

## 3\. Information Collection

Where Appen collects your personal information, Appen will take reasonable steps to notify you, via this policy displayed on our website, of: 

  * The purposes for which we are collecting the information; 
  * The third parties to whom we may disclose the information of that kind; 
  * Whether any of those third parties are located overseas, and if practicable to specify, the countries in which they are located; and
  * How to access and correct personal information and make privacy complaints

### Information Use

Appen may use your personally identifiable information to provide you with the services you request, maintain our accounts, for billing and payment, to enable us to answer your enquiries, for verifying your identity for security purposes, for marketing our services and products and to help make our website as useful to you as possible for purposes consistent with this policy. These uses may generally be categorized as relationship maintenance uses and promotional uses. We describe these uses in more detail below.

### Relationship Maintenance Uses

Appen uses your personally identifiable information to maintain and manage your account, deliver services that you have requested, and generally enhance your experience on our Website. Collectively, we refer to these types of uses as “Relationship Maintenance Uses,” and they include all of the ways in which we use your personally identifiable information to maintain and manage our relationship with you that do not involve sending promotional materials. Examples of Relationship Maintenance Uses include, but are not limited to:

  * Processing and tracking your independent contractor qualifications; 
  * Processing and tracking your profile information;
  * Providing the services you request;
  * Sending you updates and notices about system updates or outages;
  * Sending you other administrative communications;
  * Sending you surveys;
  * Sending you updates to our privacy policy; and
  * Making changes to Web-based features

## 4\. Information Sharing and Disclosure

In providing our products and services, or collecting and using your personal information, your personal information may be disclosed to third party organizations including: 

  * Information technology service providers;
  * Marketing and communications agencies;
  * Mailing houses, freight and courier services; 
  * Printers and distributors of direct marketing material; 
  * Our legal, accounting, financial or other professional advisors; and 
  * Regulatory, government and other authorities required by law 

## 5\. Opting Out

By providing us with your contact details, your consent to receive communications and direct marketing will remain current until you advise us otherwise. However, you can opt out at any time through the following channels:

By mail – Appen Pty Ltd., Level 6, 9 Help Street Chatswood NSW 2067 

By email – [privacy@appen.com](mailto:privacy@appen.com)

Or you can use the unsubscribe facility that we include in our electronic messages such as emails.

Appen will not share your e-mail address with any third parties.

## 6\. Links to Other Sites

We may provide links on our Website to other sites we think you will enjoy. These sites operate independently of Appen and have established their own privacy and security policies. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read these policies at any site you visit.

## 7\. Information Security

We take a number of steps to safeguard any personally identifiable information that you provide to us. However, no method of transmitting or storing electronic data is ever completely secure, and therefore we cannot warrant or guarantee that such information will never be accessed, used or released in a manner that is inconsistent with this policy.

## 8\. Unsolicited Information

Unsolicited personal information is personal information we receive that we have taken no active steps to collect. If the information we receive is not required for Appen to perform one or more of our services or activities, Appen will destroy or de-identify the information as soon as practicable.

## 9\. Children’s Privacy

Our Website is not intended for use by any persons under the age of 18 years old, and we do not knowingly collect information about children. We do not sell products or services to children. If you are under 18, you may use this site only with involvement of a parent or guardian.

## 10\. Changes in this Privacy Policy

We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time. If we make any material changes in the way we collect, use, and/or share your personally identifiable information, we will notify you by sending you an e-mail at the last e-mail address that you provided us and/or by prominently posting notice of the changes on the Websites covered by this Privacy Policy. In any event, changes to this Privacy Policy may affect our use of personally identifiable information that you provided us prior to our notification to you of the changes.

This policy was last updated on 22 June 2016.

## 11\. Complaints

If you have a complaint about how Appen has collected, stored or used your personal information, please contact Appen’s head office. We will endeavour to deal with your complaint and take any necessary steps to resolve the matter within 5 business days. If your complaint is unable to be resolved within 5 business days, Appen will advise you in writing letting you know when we expect to provide our response. 

If you are unhappy with our response, you can refer your complaint to the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner. 

Please contact Appen if you have any queries about the personal information that Appen holds about you or the way we use or disclose that personal information. Our contact details are set out below. 

Address – Appen Pty Ltd., Level 6, 9 Help Street Chatswood NSW 2067 

Email – [privacy@appen.com](mailto:privacy@appen.com)
